(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-07T13:43:22.397971",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
静寂に響いてよ My Howling
Resound through the silence, my howling!
瞬きは弧描き 月へ響く
Blinks draw an arc, echoing toward the moon.
爪弾く道 金瞳の群れ 共に嘆く夜
The path of strumming, a pack of golden eyes, a night we lament together.
伝播する想いは 心強くする
The spreading feelings make our hearts stronger.
ともに行こうよ 隣に君がいるから
Let's go together, because you are by my side.
私は迷わない 光射す道へ
I won't hesitate, toward the path where light shines.
Listen to my howling...
狼が止まることはない
A wolf will never stop.
聞こえますか 聞こえますか
Can you hear me? Can you hear me?
ハロー ハロー 聴こえますか そっちは何年？
Hello, hello, can you hear me? What year is it over there?
正しく分かり合う手段は 一つじゃないさ
The right way to understand each other isn't just one.
迷う時間はどこへ行くのか さよならはいつ誰が決めるの
Where does the wandering time go? Who decides when goodbye is?
その手に触れようと願ってる 本当さ
I'm wishing to touch your hand, truly.
永遠の夜光 君に歌う 世界中が君にいじわるでも
Eternal nocturnal light, I sing to you, even if the whole world is mean to you.
思い出して 覚えていて まぶたの裏 本当は会えるからね
Remember it, keep it in mind, behind your eyelids, because we can truly meet again.
穏やかに 健やかに 暮れる日々 君だって私だってんだね
Days passing peacefully and healthily, you and I are both like that.
消えるのは 言葉だけ
Only words fade away.
ふんわり君を抱きしめてあげるからね
Because I'll gently hold you in my arms.
泣かないで 泣かないで
Don't cry, don't cry.
変わりゆくもの 終わりゆくもの
Things that change, things that end...
ひとつ 瞬くように
...one by one, as if blinking.
確かめていたい 霞む世界に歌う
I want to make sure, singing to a hazy world.
私を どうか 忘れないで
Please, don't ever forget me,
君の記憶の底へ
deep within your memories,
淡く 甘く 滲んで
blending softly and sweetly,
ひとつになって 漂うだけ
becoming one, just floating away.
泣き出しそうな 夜の隙間を縫って
Threading through the tearful gaps of night,
私は行く 夜明けのメロウ
I go forth, the dawn's mellow melody,
君の隣で溶けて消えるほど生きて
living until I melt and fade by your side.
はい、というわけで
Yes, so anyway,
大神ミオ生誕ライブ 「晴れ待々 にわかミオ」
Ookami Mio Birthday Live "Hare Matimati Niwaka Mio"
お、見に来てくれてありがとう！
Oh, thank you for coming to see me!
ちょっと自己紹介からいこうかな。
Let's start with a self-introduction.
ということで、うっちうっち！
So, Uchi uchi!
うっちだよ、大神ミオだよ！
It's Uchi, Ookami Mio!
はー、よろしくお願いします！
Haah, nice to meet you!
まあ大体の人はね、知ってると思うんですけども、これを機会に観てみようかなという人は是非是非大神ミオをよろしくお願いします！
Well, most of you probably know, but if anyone's checking it out for the first time, please give Ookami Mio lots of love!
えー、今日のハッシュタグは、こちら！たくさんポストの方よろしくお願いします！
Um, today's hashtag is right here! Please post lots on X!
さてさて、生誕ライブ始まったわけなんだけど
Now then, the birthday live has started,
ステージすごくない？こんなに大きいステージ作ってもらったよ！
Isn't the stage amazing? They made such a huge stage for me!
なんかビルとか建ってるし、ここはいったいどこなんだというこで天井もめっちゃ広いんだけど
There are buildings and stuff, and I wonder where on earth this is, the ceiling is also super high, but
なんかね、うっちがね、魔法の言葉を言うとね、なんかどっかが暮らすんだよね。ちょっと開けてみろって言われてるの。ちょっと行きますよ。
you know, when I say magic words, somewhere lights up. I was told to try opening it. Here I go.
せーの、オープン！
Ready, set, open!
うわー、すごい！
Whoa, amazing!
交々し、うわー！
So majestic, whoa!
空だー！
It's the sky!
ということで、タイトルからちょっとだけ予想はつくかもしれないんだけれども、晴れだったり雨だったり昼だったり夜だったり
So, you might have guessed a bit from the title, but whether it's sunny, rainy, daytime, or nighttime,
いろんな要素を表現したいといううっちの要望を全部叶えてもらいましたー！すごい素敵なステージありがとうございます！
all of Uchi's wishes to express various elements came true! Thank you for such a wonderful stage!
おっきよー！
Thank you so much!
えー、上さん、どうもありがとうございます。いつもお世話になってます。
Um, Ue-san, thank you very much. I'm always in your care.
ということで、え、みんなもね、いっぱいお祝いしてくれてどうもありがとね！
So, um, everyone, thank you so much for celebrating with me!
うちはホロライブに入って、もう6回目の誕生日なんですけれども
I joined Hololive, and this is already my 6th birthday, but
ま、なんか、なんかね、なんかしらっていつもね、誕生日ケーキ食べれてないんだけどね。
well, somehow, for some reason, I never seem to be able to eat birthday cake.
今年は、ま、ちょっと体調を崩したこともあり、ちょっと多分ケーキは食べられないんだけど
This year, well, having caught a bit of a cold, I probably can't eat cake, but
今日はその代わりに大好きなホロライブのメンバーと一緒にたくさん歌おうと思ってます！
today, instead, I'm planning to sing a lot together with my beloved Hololive members!
え、それぞれメンバーと一緒に歌いたい曲をたくさん選曲してみました！
Um, I've carefully selected many songs I want to sing together with each member!
ここからホロメンとのコラボ曲、もりだくさんでお送りしちゃいます！
From here on, we'll be delivering plenty of collaboration songs with Holomem!
は、もう次の曲の準備をしなきゃいけないかもしれない、しれない、噛んじゃったけど
Ha, I might have to prepare for the next song, though I stumbled on my words,
最後までみんなたくさん楽しんでってね！
everyone, please enjoy it to the very end!
じゃ、ちょっと準備してくるね。楽しんでねー！
Well then, I'll go get ready. Have fun!
貴方は風のように
You are like the wind,
目を閉じては夕暮れ
closing your eyes at sunset.
何を思っているんだろうか
What are you thinking about?
目蓋を開いていた
With your eyelids open,
貴方の目はビイドロ
your eyes were like glass.
少しだけ晴れの匂いがした
It faintly smelled like a sunny day.
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け
Clear up the sky, let flowers bloom,
咲いて晴れのせい
bloom and blame it on the sunny sky!
降り止めば雨でさえ
Even the rain, when it stops,
貴方を飾る晴る
makes you shine in the sunlight.
胸を打つ音よ凪げ
Calm the stirring sounds in my heart,
僕ら晴る風
We go like the sunny wind,
あの雲も...
that cloud too...
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠く まだ遠くまで
Beyond those clouds, keep going further, far, still far away.
残酷だったよな人生は
How cruel life can be,
思ってよりいま君に会って
meeting you now more than I thought,
思いきり泣いてみたい
I want to cry my heart out.
終わりは何方も告げず 始まった
Without a word of ending, it began,
朝が来ない部屋で 燃やした恋も
in a room where morning never comes, the burning love too,
このプライドや劣等じゃ 闘えないと知る
knowing I can't fight with just this pride and inferiority.
残酷だったよな人生は
How cruel life can be,
思ってよりいま君に会って 思いきり泣いてみたい
meeting you now more than I thought, I want to cry my heart out.
どうにかなるはずさ どうにかなるはずさ
It'll work out somehow, it'll work out somehow,
どうにもならなかった
but it just didn't work out at all.
僕らの日々には 名前は付けないで
Don't give names to our days,
想い出になるほど 綺麗じゃないから
because they aren't pretty enough to become memories.
あの海も越えてゆけ
Beyond that sea too, keep going,
遠く まだ遠くまで
far, still far away.
背広がお似合いないと 肩叩き笑い合った
Laughing together and patting shoulders as suits didn't suit us,
あいつの猫背が 急に恋しいぜ
I suddenly miss that hunched back of theirs.
惨々なんだよな人生は わかっちいたけど
How miserable life can be, even though I already knew it,
いまお前に会って話したいな 話したいよ
I want to meet you now and talk, I really want to talk.
残酷だったよな人生は
How cruel life can be,
思ってよりいま君に会って
meeting you now more than I thought,
思いきり泣いてみたい
I want to cry my heart out.
ハッピーエンドへの期待は 捨てないで
Don't abandon hope for a happy ending,
どうか元気でね
please take care of yourself.
あの雲も越えてゆけ
Beyond those clouds, keep going further,
遠く まだ遠くまで
far, still far away.
今なんじゃない？ メラメラとたぎれ
Isn't it now? Blaze up fiercely,
眠っているだけの正義
justice that's just been sleeping.
こんな僕も 君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even a guy like me wants to be your hero!
Mela! Lalala...
かっこいい君には 僕じゃ頼りないのかななんて
Wondering if I'm too unreliable compared to someone as cool as you,
そりゃそうだよなだって今もこうして迷ってる
well of course you are, since I'm still hesitating like this.
手を取ってくれないか ギブとテイクさ
Won't you take my hand? It's give and take.
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero,
今なんじゃない？ メラメラとたぎれ
isn't it now? Blaze up fiercely,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
the justice lurking even inside someone like me.
どうしようもない衝動にかられて ほら気付けば手を握っている
Swept up by an uncontrollable impulse, before I knew it, I'm holding your hand.
いったいぜんたい そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Just how much baggage are you carrying as you go off somewhere?
ねぇねぇ待って僕にちょっと預けてみては？
Hey, wait, why don't you entrust a little of it to me?
信じてばかりの僕と
With only belief in myself,
信じる事が怖い君と
and you, who are afraid to believe,
どちらが正しいのかなんて
which of us is right
誰にも分からないさ
nobody knows.
僕らだけの世界
Our own world,
ギブとテイクさ
give and take.
補い合えた暁には
When we compensate for each other,
同じ夢を見たい
I want to see the same dream.
君はかっこいいと苦しめて
Hurting yourself thinking you have to be cool,
ひとりぼっちにさせたのは
and leaving yourself all alone
少し僕のせいなんだよなごめんね
was partly my fault, I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But what we need to look at is reality.
今こそ僕が救うんだ
Now is the time I will save you.
抱えないで信じて頼ってほしいんだ
Don't hold it in; believe in me and rely on me.
今なんじゃない? メラメラとたぎる こんな僕にも潜む正義が
Isn't it now? The burning justice hidden even inside me
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
driven by an uncontrollable impulse,
ほら気付けば手を握っている
look, before I knew it, our hands were joined.
ほとけない そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
You can't leave it be! Carrying so much luggage, where are you going?
ほんのちょっと 僕にちょっと預けてみては?
Won't you entrust just a little bit of it to me?
こんな僕も 君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even a guy like me wants to be your hero!
じょいふる
Joyful!
キミノコエヲキカセテ
Let me hear your voice!
サアボウケンシテミナイ
Why don't we go on an adventure?
タノシイコトハジメヨウ
Let's start something fun!
遊いたい!
I want to play!
ぜったい JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイビー
Definitely, with JOY and JOY and JOY, a POP baby!
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
JOY and JOY and JOY, HAPPY people!
キミノヒトミニチスシテ笑いたい!
Kissing your eyes, I want to laugh!
ヨワムシナンカじゃない
I'm not a coward!
ジシンアリゲニピースサイン
Throwing a confident peace sign!
キミノヒトミニキスシテ笑いたい!
Kissing your eyes, I want to laugh!
ぜったい ぜったい ぜったい
Definitely, definitely, definitely!
JOY と JOY と JOY と YOUきなベイビー
JOY and JOY and JOY, a courageous baby!
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなSayイエー
JOY and JOY and JOY, HAPPY Say Yeah!
君の心はそう もっと Do Do
Your heart is like that, even more Do Do,
僕の心もそう いっそ Good Good
my heart is like that too, much better Good Good!
はじけかるんじゃない イッツ ジョイフル
Aren't we bursting out? It's Joyful!
パピプペポバブーン イエー!
Papipupepo baboon, yeah!
JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイビー
JOY and JOY and JOY, a POP baby!
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピーポー
JOY and JOY and JOY, HAPPY people!
ドキドキしちゃうのなんでだろう
Why does my heart go dokidoki?
ズキズキしちゃうのなんでだろう
Why does my heart go zukizuki?
この指に止まるのは どんな運命なんだ全部したいな
Whatever fate lands on this finger, I want to do it all!
じょいふるだって終わっちゃう エビバディいつか終わっちゃう
Even joyfulness will end, everybody will end someday.
いついつも この時も 最終型はきっと思案なしで
Always, at this time too, the final form is definitely without a doubt.
どう We Do We Do We Do We Do Do
Do We Do We Do We Do Do!
パピプペポパピプペポ痛いっ! とだいっ! とたいっ! とたいっ!
Papipupepo papipupepo ouch! That's it! That's it!
I Wanna Joy! So Joy! To Joy! To Happy なピーポー!
I Wanna Joy! So Joy! To Joy! To Happy people!
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなSayイエー
Joy and Joy and Joy and a happy Say Yeah!
君の心はそう もっと Do Do
Your heart does, more Do Do,
僕の心もそう いっそ Good Good
My heart too, rather Good Good,
初めてなんじゃない？ イッツ・ジョイフル
Isn't this a first? It's joyful!
ぱぴぷぺぽばぶぅ〜ジョイ
Papipupepo babuu~ Joy!
晴れ待々 にわかミオ / Ookamimio Anniversary Live
[Ookamimio Anniversary Live]
エマージェンシー 0時
Emergency, 0 o'clock,
奴らはクレイジーインザタウン
they're crazy in the town,
家に籠って
shutting themselves inside,
ゴロゴロ ゴロゴロと
rolling, rolling around,
堕落の夜に絡みついた
entangled in the night of depravity.
ルルル
Rururu...
放つ言葉は
The words I release
ルルル 腐っていた
Rururu... were rotting away.
正論も常識も意味を持たない都市にサヨナラ！
Say goodbye to a city where reason and common sense mean nothing!
引きこもり絶対ジャスティス 俺の私だけの檻の中で
Hikikomori absolute justice, inside my very own cage,
聴き殺してランデブー 俺の私の音が君に染まるまで
listening and killing in a rendezvous, until my sound stains you.
引きこもり絶対ジャスティス 俺の私だけの檻の中で
Hikikomori absolute justice, inside my very own cage,
聴き殺してランデブー 俺の私の音を君が包むだけ
listening and killing in a rendezvous, just having my sound embraced by you.
Wowow 時がきた今
Wowow, the time has come now,
Wowow エゴ放つのさ
Wowow, unleashing my ego,
Wowow 家に籠って狂い咲く
Wowow, shutting myself inside and blooming madly.
エマージェンシー 0時 流石に
Emergency, 0 o'clock, as expected,
クレイジーな計画はお陀仏
the crazy plan is dead and gone,
グルグル グルグルと
going round and round,
世界は変わらず廻っていた
the world kept spinning on unchanged.
ルルル
Rururu...
君の視線が
Your gaze
ルルル ぼやけて尽きる
Rururu... blurs out and fades.
マリオネットな感情に気付いてしまった
I've realized my marionette-like emotions.
相変わらずJamる街
In the same old jamming town,
止まぬNervousに攫われないで
don't get swept away by the ceaseless nervous.
引きこもり絶対ジャスティス 俺の私だけの檻の中で
Hikikomori absolute justice, inside my very own cage,
聴き殺してランデブー 俺の私の音が君に染まるまで
listening and killing in a rendezvous, until my sound stains you.
引きこもり絶対ジャスティス 俺の私だけの檻の中で
Hikikomori absolute justice, inside my very own cage,
聴き殺してランデブー 俺の私の音を君が包むだけ
listening and killing in a rendezvous, just having my sound embraced by you.
Wowow 時がきた今
Wowow, the time has come now,
Wowow エゴ放て
Wowow, unleash your ego,
恥を捨てられるこの場所に狂い咲け
bloom madly in this place where you can cast away shame!
存在証明 愛だって 愛だって 吐いたって
Proof of existence, even if I spit out 'it's love, it's love',
ああ転んでゴロンで厭厭 プリティプリティダイエットDAY
ah, falling down and rolling around, reluctant, pretty pretty diet day,
曖昧にカイラツに 曖昧にカイラツに
Vaguely to pleasure, vaguely to pleasure,
病み悪化してんだって 愛だ恋だなんだってんだ
my illness is getting worse, they say it's love, romance, whatever.
生命線は 愛だって 愛だって 嘆いたって
Even if I lament that my lifeline is love, love,
ああでもない こうでもないな 寂しい寂しいナンセンスDAY
nothing is right, nothing is fitting, a lonely, lonely nonsense day.
いっとみいカイラツに 接吻いカイラツに
A brief look to pleasure, a kiss to pleasure,
劣れ劣れ 劣れ劣れ劣れ
Inferior, inferior, inferior, inferior, inferior,
なにもない なにもない 私なにもない
nothing at all, nothing at all, I have nothing at all.
変われない 変われない 私変われない
I can't change, I can't change, I cannot change.
分からない 分からない 分かる分からない
I don't understand, I don't understand, I understand, I don't understand.
はい目元以外を確保して
Yes, securing everything except my eyes,
だだだだだたりだりだりだり だーりんファニー
Da-da-da-da-dary-dary-dary-dary, darling funny!
「冴えない」愛情論でおねだり
With a dubitable theory of love, I'm pleading...
ダダダダダリダリ、ダーリン、dirty and dirty
Da-da-da-da-darling, dirty and dirty,
会いたい衝動 埋めてよダダダリ、ダーリン
Please fill this urge to meet you, da-da-darling!
無い無い純情感情が行ったり来たり
Purity and emotion swing back and forth,
無い無い純情感情でダダダリ、ダーリン、ちゅ
With innocence and sentiment, oh darling, chu!
ダダダダダリダリ、ダーリン、愛だ、喘いだだって
Da-da-da-da-darling, I'm gasping for love!
まみコロングループにゃんにゃん、食い意地、食い意地、ダイエットday
Gluttony, gluttony, diet day,
もう一杯で詰み、暴論世界で無理
I'm already at my limit, a hopeless worldwide blunder!
病み悪化してんだって承認、承認、接待だ
Sickly days mean I just want attention and reception!
なにもない、なにもない、私なにもない、ねぇ
I have nothing, I have nothing, I have nothing, hey!
はしたない、はしたない、私したない、ねぇ
I haven't done anything, I haven't done anything, hey!
わからない、わからない、わかる、わからない
I don't get it, I don't get it, I get it, I don't get it!
はい、自撮りは全部加工して(ぱﾟん)
Alright, hiding everything but the eyes!
ダダダダダリダリ、ダーリン、funny
Da-da-da-da-darling, darling, funny!
はい、絶えない愛情論で冷めたり
With a cold theory of love, I'm cooling down...
ダダダダダリダリ、無理、dirty and dirty
Da-da-da-da-darling, it's impossible!
会いたい衝動止めてよ、ダダダリ、ダーリン
Please stop this urge to meet you, da-da-darling!
踊れ、叫べ
Dance! Shout!
踊れ、ルラパパ
Dance, ru-la-pa-pa!
踊れ、歌え
Dance! Sing!
踊れ、ルラパパ
Dance, ru-la-pa-pa!
もうドキンドキンの脳、しんどき、期の、ドキん、悩み
Heart pounding in my brain, a thrilling dilemma!
はい、素顔は全部無くして(ぱﾟん)
Alright, making my bare face completely disappear!
ダダダダダリダリ、ダーリン、funny
Da-da-da-da-darling, funny!
どうしようもない感情論に笑ったり
Laughing at these helpless emotional arguments,
ダダダダダリダリ、ダーリン、dirty and dirty
Da-da-da-da-darling, dirty and dirty,
会いたい衝動埋めてよダダダリ、ダーリン
Please fill this urge to meet you, da-da-darling!
無い無い反応、返答を期待したり
No response, expecting a reply, expecting it!
無い無い妄想感情でダダダリ、ダーリン
No delusions, with my sappy feelings, da-da-darling!
無い無い純情感情でダダダリ、ダーリン、ちゅ
No purity, with my sappy feelings, da-da-darling, chu!
ドキドキしてrouge？いけますよ〜！
Beating with rouge? Let's go!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Not guilty! Beautiful girl, not guilty!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine is not guilty!
やっぱキラキラもっとクラクラ
Shining bright, making me even more dizzy!
ねえ、言ったよね？年齢なんて関係ないってさ
Hey, didn't you say age doesn't matter?
そういうめんどくさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
That you'd love me with all my troubles too!
ねえねえ、言ったよね？言ってない？
Hey, didn't you say? Or did you not?
ふーん、そういうこと言うんだ。
Hmm, is that so?
まかせて！魔法で若返り
Leave it to me! Staying young with magic!
ヒミツの素顔はキミにだけ
My true face is just for you!
トクベツですよ〜！
It's special, you know?
宝の島にしてほしい気分
I want you to make this a treasure island!
出航ー！！
Set sail!
キュートは正義、美少女無罪
Cute is justice, innocent pretty girl!
キミの一番目指してヨーソロー！
Aiming to be number one in your heart, yo-ho-ho!
本当は自信ないけど頑張っちゃう(ahoy！！)
I'm lacking confidence, but I'll do my best! (Ahoy!)
恋する気持ち17歳
Falling in love, my heart feels 17 years old,
0時になっちゃうわオトナの時間
When midnight strikes, it's time to be an adult!
ドキドキしてrouge？まだ早い♡
Beating with rouge? Still too early!
だっ、だっ、ダメですか？フリルの服着たら
Is it not allowed if I wear ruffled clothes?
魔法少女になってみたい(ギリギリ有罪！？)
I want to be a magical girl! (Barely guilty?!)
進度はななみ星、ちょっぴり足りない積極性？
Destination? Towards the dream star!
結局キミももっと若い子？なんだってするから
You prefer younger girls too, don't you?
見せないでキミと、ちょっとイイトコ見せてみた〜い！
Let me show off a little bit!
出航ー！！
Set sail!
ハートにチャーム美少女無罪
Cute is justice, innocent pretty girl!
あれあれどーした？めんどくさいなんて言っちゃって
Why are you sulking and saying it's a bother?
かまってくれるキミが好き(はいっ)
I love how you still care about me!
優しくしてね17歳
Be nice to me, okay? I'm 17 years old!
突っ込んで経験値お楽しみchu♡
Gain experience, let's enjoy chu!
お許しくださ〜い！このマリンの…
Please forgive me! This Marine...
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge?
Beating fast, rouge?
いきますよ〜！
Here we go~!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Innocent! Innocent! Beautiful girl innocent!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Still sparkling, even more dizzying
離さないで つかまっていて
Don't let go, hold on tight
世界の広さ 見せつけてあげるから！
I'll show you how vast the world is!
出航ーー！！
Set sail!!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, innocent beautiful girl
キミの一番目指して よーそろー！
Aiming to be your number one, yo-ho-ro!
冗談も大好きだけど 真剣よ
I love jokes too, but I'm serious
Ahoy!!
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんっ
Kyu kyu kyurun
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるるんっ
Kyu kyu kyururun
恋する気持ち 17歳
Feeling in love at 17 years old
0時になっちゃうわ オトナの時間
Turning midnight, it's adult time
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Still sparkling, even more dizzying
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge? まだ早い♡
Beating fast, rouge? Still too early ♡
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Innocent! Innocent! Beautiful girl innocent!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Still sparkling, even more dizzying
“マリン”じゃなくて “マリン船長”だろん！？
Not "Marine," but "Captain Marine," right!?
“マリン”じゃなくて “マリン船長”だろっ！？
電波テンポアップして絶賛感電中！
Radio wave tempo up, electrified in acclaim!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
あなたにもわすれたいことかないこと あるのかしらね
I wonder if there are things you want to forget too
知らない映画なのに涙をながすのは ドラマチックが足りないからよ
Shedding tears at an unknown movie is because there's a lack of drama
そんな愚にも付かないこと くだらないこと考えてばかりね
Always thinking about such foolish and pointless things
雨が上がれば愛もその横顔も誰かのものになるのでしょう
When the rain stops, love and that profile will belong to someone else
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部 今夜のためよ
All the fake foundations are for tonight
なのに一体全体何をして何故何故張ってんの
But why on earth, why are you putting on airs?
不安定なカンテラ どこまで行くの
Unstable lantern, how far will you go?
あなた一切合切放り去って もう冗談じゃないわ
Throwing everything away, I'm not joking around
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が来たって如何にもならないぜ
Even if that time comes, nothing can be done
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
Vague truths only turn into melancholia
あたしをさっさとさらって今テイクオンミー
Snatch me away and take me on now
はあ ちゃんちゃらおかしな法度ばっかで
Ha, with all these ridiculous laws
実態の無い感情放っておいたって 策略なんてありゃあせんのに何故
Pointless emotions left behind, even though there's no strategy, why?
うん あぁもう懲り懲りよ あたしのカッとなる気質もじっと堪えて取り繕ってわとうとう限界点
Yeah, I've had enough. My quick temper too, holding it in and putting up a front until my breaking point
年から年中リップサービス 鈍感かましてはひびきドンガラガシャンフィールガールは涙の目にも鬼
Year-round lip service, acting dense, crashing feel girl is a demon even in tears
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいで あなたの話は一向に聴き取れない 少しは真面目なこと言って
Now because of the music in my head, I can't hear your words at all. Say something serious for once
回り出すターンテーブル ねぇ全部忘れさせてよ
The turntable starts spinning. Hey, let me forget everything
だけど一体全体如何してどうして なぜなぜ張ってんな
But why on earth, why why are you putting on airs?
不安定なカンテラ 消えないわかんね
Unstable lantern, it won't go out
あなた一口両舌食い違ってもう
You're double-tongued and conflicting
冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not joking, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が来たって如何にもならないぜ
Even if that time comes, nothing can be done
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
Vague truths only turn into melancholia
あたしを今
Me right now
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ その時が来たって如何にもならないぜ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, even if that time comes, nothing can be done
不甲斐ないわ 感情なんてランドリーで落とすだけ
It's pathetic, just wash away emotions in the laundry
あたしと確かめ合ってイエローマジック
Confirming with me, yellow magic
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ その時が来たって如何にもならないぜ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, even if that time comes, nothing can be done
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリ化するだけ
Vague truths only turn into melancholia
あたしをさっさとさらって今テイクオンミー
Snatch me away and take me on now
はい！というわけで連続で7曲もお送りしましたわー！
Yes! And with that, we've delivered 7 songs in a row~!
いやいっぱい歌った歌った！ みんなめちゃ可愛かったな！
Man, I sang and sang! Everyone was super cute!
半分うちの趣味…まあというかもほとんどうちの趣味で選曲させてもらったんですけれども
Half of it was my hobby... well, actually most of it was my hobby in song selection,
きっとねみんなもね、うちが歌うの初めての楽曲ばかりだったと思うんですが、みんなどうだったかな？
I'm sure for many of you, these were songs you've never heard me sing before, how was it everyone?
まだまだね、もうちょっと歌う続くんだけれども
There's still a bit more singing left, but
その前にみなさんおまちかね！ グッズ…
Before that, everyone's long-awaited! Goods...
紹介です！イエーイ！
Let's introduce them! Yay!
今年のグッズはなにかなどこかなというわけで！
Wonder what this year's merch is?
はい、こちらです！バーバン！
Well, here it is! Ta-da!
今回も泉パパにキービジュアルを描いてもらいました！
かっこいいみおだ、がおポーズ。
We had Izumi Papa draw key visuals again!
Look at that cute Mio pose.
色々ね、ちょっともう見えちゃってるんだけれども！
I'm already giving away some spoilers, but...
まずは、こちら！アクリルスタンドです！
First up is this, the acrylic stand!
このね、がおポーズのアクリルスタンド可愛いんだよね！
This, you know, "rawr" pose acrylic stand
is so cute, right?
しかもこれ、ただのアクリルスタンドではなくて、
なんと、ミラーコーティングでキラキラしてまーす！
And get this—it's not just a regular stand,
it has a mirror coating and is super sparkly!
うちがね、あの個人的にねキラキラなアクリルスタンド作りたくって、
わがままを聞いてもらって、ミラーコーティングにしてもらいました！いえーい！
I personally wanted a sparkly acrylic stand,
so I had them make it with a mirror coating! Yay!
ミオファもね、足元にいてね、可愛いね！
うちも部屋に飾ろうっと！はい。
MioFa are at our feet, how cute!
I'll display this in my room too!
そしてお次、2つ目は！Tシャツです！可愛い！
And next, the second item is... a T-shirt!
So cute!
こちらもキービジュアルを使ったTシャツとなっております！
泉パパに描いてもらったイラストなんだけど、
This also features the key visual.
The illustration was drawn by Izumi Papa...
このね、かっこいいTシャツを作るために
描いてもらったといっても過言ではないイラストとなっておりまして、
ちょっとコロックな感じに仕上げてもらいましたのでね！
To make this cool T-shirt,
he finished it with a really dope, cool vibe!
はい、かっこいいからみんなも日常生活にいかがでしょうか！
サイズはちょっと大きめのXLサイズ。
It's cool, so I hope you all wear it
in your daily lives! Size is XL, pretty big.
プリントもね、すごいくっきくて、結構目立つから、
イベントに来ていって、ミオファをアピールしてね！
The print is also huge and very noticeable,
so wear it to events and rep MioFa!
そして3つ目！サコッシュ！
And third... a sacoche bag!
最近さ、なんかいたばを作ってる人いっぱい見かけるし、
なんかホロライブ公式からもたくさんいたば用のバッグとか出してるの見て、
まあ、他のメンバーもね、バッグ出してるのを見てさ、
うちもなんかバッグ、ミオファ用に作りたいかもと思って、サコッシュを作ってみました！
Lately, I see a lot of people making sacoches,
and Hololive Production made a bunch for events,
so I thought I'd make a MioFa version too!
まあサコッシュなんで、あの、
お財布とか、あの、スマホとかをね、ちょっと入れとくいいんですけども、
まあ、あの、外、外側のポケットが透明になってるから、そこにカンバッチを入れたりとか、
ちょっといたばにすることもできるし、なんかこうちょっとグッズを入れてアピールすることもできるバッグとなっております！
Since it's a sacoche, you can put your wallet
or phone in it, but the outer pocket is clear,
so you can put a can badge or make it an itaba!
はい！まあ、本当にね、なんかこう、ちょっと、まあ、荷物用で一袋持って、
お財布とか取り出しやすいようにこのサコッシュを1個持ってると使いやすいかなと思って作りました！
I made this thinking it would be easy to use
if you just hold one bag for your luggage.
はい、そして最後の4つ目！こちらです！
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー、可愛い！
And finally, the fourth item...
a plush keychain in hoodie outfit ver.! Cute!
4つ目はぬいぐるみキーホルダーパーカー衣装のぬいぐるみバージョンです！
これがね、パーカーは初めてなんだよ！めっちゃ可愛い！
The fourth item is a plush keychain
in her hoodie outfit! This is her first hoodie version!
サコッシュにね、一緒に付けてね、なんかちょうどいいまであるよね、うん。
Attach it to your sacoche, it's just the right size!
絶対一緒に付けてほしい！一緒にうちをお出かけに連れてってほしいな！
You definitely gotta attach it together,
take me out on your outings!
パーカーの衣装だとね、こうちょっとラフな感じでお出かけも連れて行きやすいんじゃないでしょうか！
あ、落とさないようにね、皆さん絶対に気をつけてくださいね！
Hoodie outfits have that rough vibe,
so it's easy to take out on trips!
Just don't drop it, please be careful!
はい！そしてこの4つのグッズ、フルセットで注文していただくと、
なんと特典としてこちら！
複製サイン入り＆メッセージ入りのキービジュアルのダイカットステッカーと、
あと、誕生日ありがとうのウチのお礼ボイスがついてきまーす！わー！
And if you order these four goods as a full set,
you'll get a facsimile signed & messaged key visual die-cut sticker
and a thank-you voice as a bonus!
いやーちょっとね、フルセット購入悩んでいる方、ぜひぜひこの特典もね、目当てに、あの、買ってくれたら嬉しいなんて思うんですけれどもし、まあ、お小遣いもね限られてたりとかするから、まあ、あの、お財布と相談しながら買って下さい！よろしくお願いします！
というわけで、以上グッズ紹介でした！
So if you're thinking of buying the full set,
please grab these bonuses too!
Look forward to it!
今年の生誕グッズも、もうリラックスなんだな！もう全部のグッズがね、あの、うちが、あの、こういうグッズがいいです、こういうグッズがいいですって言って、全部あの監修して、あのこだわりを持って作ったので、ぜひぜひ皆さんのお手元に届くのを楽しみにしてます！ぜひ届いたら、えー写真を撮って、ポスートしてくださいね！うちのお家に届くのもすっごい楽しみだな！というわけで、まだまだ、もうちょっとだけライブは続くんですが、
This year's birthday merch is super relaxing,
I put my own preferences and care into all of them.
I hope you look forward to getting them!
まずはゲストでまだ出てないメンバーがいますよねー！うーん、楽しみだな！
あの透明感ある声がいいんだよな！
First, there are still some guest members
who haven't appeared yet! Yay, I'm so excited!
I love that transparent vibe in voices.
そしてなんとなんと！新曲も！お披露目しちゃいます！やったー！ついにやお披露目だ！
And what's more...
Our new song is also premiering! Yay, finally!
に公開する予定ですので、そちらも一緒に宜しくお願いいたします。
It's scheduled to be released publicly, so I hope you'll check that out too.
そしてライブの後にはメンバーシップ限定アンコールライブもあるよ！
And after the live, there's also a membership-exclusive encore live!
すごい！メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブ、実は初めてやるんです。よろしくお願いします！ぜひ見に来てね。
Amazing! This is actually our first time doing a membership-exclusive encore live. Please come watch!
それでは、大神ミオ 生誕ライブ 晴れ時々 望みオ、残も少なくなってきましたが、最後まで一緒に盛り上がっていこう！
Now then, Ookami Mio's Birthday Live 'Sunny, Occasionally Mio', there's not much left, but let's get hyped together until the very end!
おー！
Let's go!
貴方の声で解れてゆく
I will unwind with your voice
忘れたくないと心が言う
My heart says I don't want to forget
思い出ばっか増えてゆく
More memories keep increasing
ずっと側に居たい
I want to stay by your side forever
泣き虫でもいいかな
It's okay to be a crybaby
強がらないでいいよ
You don't have to act strong
限りある恋だとしても
Even if it's a limited love
出逢えて幸せです
I'm happy to have met you
いつまでも
Forever and ever
続いて欲しいと願っている
I pray that this will continue
手を取ることは出来ずとも
Even if I can't take your hand
私は貴方を好きでいる
I am fond of you
貴方の夢で心安らぐ
My heart finds peace in your dreams
目覚めたくないと僕は言う
I say I don't want to wake up
思い出ばっか増えてゆく
More memories keep increasing
明日も側に居たい
I want to stay by your side tomorrow too
どこまでも
Wherever, wherever
鈍感な僕を叱って欲しい
I want you to scold insensitive me
当たり前が壊れることに気づけないくらいに子供だけどちゃんと僕は貴方を好きでいる
I'm just a child who can't even notice when the ordinary falls apart, yet truly, I am fond of you
私の
My
僕の
時間が止まればいいのに
I wish time would just stop
ほらまた期待をしてしまう
See, I find myself expecting again
グッと堪えてみるからさ
I'll try my best to hold it back, so
もし溢れ出したら瞳をちゃんと見てよ見てよ見てよ
If it starts to overflow, look into my eyes properly, look, look
貴方の影だけ伸びてゆく
Only your shadow keeps stretching out
消えてしまわないでずっとずっと
Please don't disappear, always, always
この思いは変わらない
This feeling will never change
いつまでも
Forever and ever
続いて欲しいと願っている
I pray that this will continue
手を取ることは出来ずとも
Even if I can't take your hand
過ぎていく現在に抱きしめられている
I am being embraced by the passing present
私の
My
僕の
時間が止まればいいのに
I wish time would just stop.
今日を噛み締めいてよ
Let's savor today to the fullest.
終わるな 夏よ 終わるな
Don't end, summer, don't end.
どうせなら 独りでゆこう
If we're going alone anyway,
小心旅行
Timid Journey
今日は出掛けたいはきっとさ
I'm sure I want to go out today.
ああ もう 乗り換えがわかんないや
Ah, I don't get train transfers anymore.
やっつけとこっかな いわゆる便利な 世の中は
I'll just patch it up in this so-called convenient world,
ジツラほど自由じゃない
which isn't as free as it seems.
ああ どうせ 忘れちゃうのなら
Ah, if I'm just going to forget it anyway,
上書きしちゃうのなら
and overwrite it with new memories,
カメラは必要ないんだけど
I don't really need a camera,
つま先は 覚えていたい
but I want my toes to remember.
見て ああ 浅い ふた携帯と充電器 イヤホンは置いていく
Leaving behind a low-battery phone, charger, and earphones,
身軽さで スキップの 距離を稼ぐ
I travel light and skip along the distance.
ああ いや 感情はきっとさ ずっと背負うのは割に合わない
Ah no, carrying emotions around all the time just isn't worth it.
今日はつけよっかな 靴擦れじゃ困らない
Maybe I'll put some on today so I don't get blisters.
私しか 困らない
Only I would be troubled.
どうせ忘れちゃうとして 上書きしちゃうとして でもね いつかは思い出すから
Even if I'm bound to forget and overwrite it eventually, I know I'll remember someday.
しょせん人手すから お土産はいつものネット
After all, souvenirs can just be ordered online as usual.
私と猫の分 それで十分
Just enough for me and my cat.
ああ 見慣れた家電に安心する カーテンはうちの匂い 離れて気付く 私の輪郭
Familiar appliances bring comfort; the curtains smell like home. Being away makes me realize who I am.
少々真面目の傷心旅行
A somewhat serious heartbroken journey.
誰にも言わずに家を出る
I left home without telling a soul.
結局知でいる店に逃げ この少々さえ愛してる
I end up escaping to a familiar shop, and I love even this foolishness.
ああ 安心状態の傷心旅行から 戻ったよと伝えたい
Ah, I want to tell you I've returned from my heartbroken journey with a peaceful mind.
それが誰かわからないけど あなただといい ただいま 帰ったよ
I don't know who you are, but I hope it's you. I'm back, I'm home.
雨燦々
Ame Sansan
選べよ 変わりゆく時代を
Choose the changing times,
割り切れなくとも
even if you can't make sense of it all.
この瞬間 この舞台を生き抜くから
Because in this moment, on this stage, I will survive it all.
手答えの無い 今日でさえも
Even on days like today, which offer no answers...
紡ぐよ でこぼこな此の道に
We weave our tale along this bumpy road.
降り注ぐ 雨燦々と
As the rain pours down brilliantly,
と悩ましき
troubled and perplexed,
生き惑う僕らの
we wander through life.
悲しみさえも 水に流してゆく
Washing away even our sadness with the water.
錆びついた 自転車を走らせて
Riding on a rusted bicycle,
君へと向かうのさ
I'm heading towards you.
雨に濡れながら帰ろう
Let's go home, getting soaked in the rain.
臨時ニュースの報せでは
According to a breaking news flash,
どうやらこれから 土砂降りの雨が降るらしい
it seems a heavy downpour is about to start.
傘を忘れた ため息は
The sigh of leaving my umbrella behind
夕立ちが連れてきた 夏の匂いに解けてゆく
dissolves into the scent of summer brought by the evening shower.
過去を呪う悲しみ達が 雲となり雨を打ちつける
The sorrows cursing the past turn into clouds and beat down rain.
叫べよ 気の晴れるまで
Scream out until your spirit clears,
声は 雨にかき消され
your voice drowned out by the rain.
今じゃ何処の誰にも届かなくても
Even if it doesn't reach anyone anywhere now,
手遅れになってしまった 未来へさえも
and even to a future that has become too late,
繋ぐよ そのバトンを
we pass on that baton.
静かに待っている人がいる
There are people waiting quietly.
雨燦々と 悩ましき
Pouring down brilliantly, troubled...
生き惑う僕らの
we wander through life.
悲しみさえも 水に流してゆく
Washing away even our sadness with the water.
線路沿い 風を切り 直線に君へと向かうのさ
Cutting through the wind along the railway, heading straight to you.
雨に濡れながら帰ろう
Let's go home, getting soaked in the rain.
みおしゃ お誕生日おめでとう！
Mio-sha, happy birthday!
みおしゃ！ お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Mio-sha! Happy birthday!
お誕生日おめでとう！ みおしゃ！ お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Mio-sha! Happy birthday!
みおしゃ！お誕生日おめでとう！ハッピーバースデー！みおしゃ！
Mio-sha! Happy birthday! Happy birthday, Mio-sha!
みおちゃん お誕生日おめでとう！みおちゃん！ハッピーバースデー！
Mio-chan, happy birthday! Mio-chan! Happy birthday!
みおちゃん お誕生日おめでとう！みおちゃん！お誕生日おめでとう！
Mio-chan, happy birthday! Mio-chan, happy birthday!
夏を泳いでずぶ濡れの 僕らを映し出す
Reflecting us, drenched from swimming through summer.
烈しく照りつける太陽よ 僕らを導いておくれよ
O sun that fervently beats down, please guide us.
未来を謳う言葉だけが 風となり森を吹き抜ける
Only words singing of the future become the wind blowing through the forest.
選べよ 変わりゆく時代を
Choose the changing era,
割り切れなくとも
even if you can't accept it fully.
この瞬間 この舞台を生き抜くから
Because in this moment, on this stage, I will survive it all.
青き春の瞬きから 何度目覚めようとも
No matter how many times we awaken from the flash of youth's spring,
紡ぐよ でこぼこな此の道に
we weave our tale along this bumpy road.
降り注ぐ 雨燦々と
As the rain pours down brilliantly,
と悩ましき
troubled and perplexed,
生き惑う僕らの
we wander through life.
悲しみさえも 水に流してゆく
Washing away even our sadness with the water.
錆びついた 自転車を走らせて 君へと向かうのさ
Riding on a rusted bicycle, I'm heading towards you.
雨に濡れながら帰ろう
Let's go home, getting soaked in the rain.
みんな お誕生日をお祝いしてくれてありがとう！ 幸福な誕生日になったよ！ 来年の誕生日も こうやってお祝いできますように！ ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you so much for celebrating my birthday! I've had such a happy birthday! I hope we can celebrate my birthday together like this next year too! Thank you!